I want to respond
to a few questions that I might not go
one by
one if I go one by one that would be a
very symptomatic approach to
it we lay down a principle and probably
all your answers you will find in the
next two presentations that I will make
there's a question about undue
familiarity many cases of men have
breaking Ladies by being so close to
them yet not interested and ending up
dating someone else trifling with one
another's Hearts maintaining boundaries
and emotional
Purity uh refer to emotional Purity and
aair of the heart how to deal with
consequences of coming from a broken
relationship or
family
mental conviction and condemnation
Nation whatever that
means Adam and Eve were the first
parents where did they Source The
Experience
from and should we use our own
experience when
parenting Kan and Abel
should we no student parent
relationship is it right for students to
stay long without going going home to
see their
parents that is over one
year what are the major effects of
this should we date while in campus
no how to know the relationship is
right as Adventist should we celebrate
Valentine's Day
Valentine is coming eh where is your
boyfriend campus dating and is it good
to date a man 10 years older than a
lady is marrying young
wrong the best way to be in
courtship I'm making two quick
presentations if there's a question that
will not be addressed there you will let
me
know allow me make a very foundational
statement that marriage must
work marriage must do
what must
work one because God the originator is
not a
failure the one that originated marriage
is not a what so there is no plan of God
that can be thwarted never it may seem
to know it's
toast here and there but it will never
fail
never his purpose for founding this
institution can never be
thed and three remember there's no
backup what plan so it must work you
like it you
don't but why has this same institution
become a source of so much
pain so much misery and sorrow with some
dismissing it as something that is not
workable
why the Lord does not add sorrow To His
blessings true or false which verse is
that yeah he had no sorrow To His
blessings so if marriage is a blessing
to man then what is all this sorrow we
are going through in
marriage why do some people quit even
before they find connection and meaning
haven't you seen weddings that have been
done after 3 months they're thinking
divorce yes some have lasted only one
year and they have gone separate ways
why is it some people quit even before
they find connection and meaning in
their marriage why have some people
decided to
redefine marriage and family just to see
if it can work and we have lots of
redefinitions of marriage today from
samesex marriages that is a redefinition
of marriage and you'll find someone was
hurt by a boyfriend and has found
consolation with another
girl and today the church is being coass
to accept gay
marriages you
[Music]
know family is a dynamic we need to be
sensitive to which
sensitivity some people today have
redefined marriage and
family and today we have baby mama
and baby
daddies and comfortably they will say
that's my baby daddy that's my baby
mama so they will get married they give
birth to a
child and then the girl marries another
man the man marries another
woman
he and then when they go for Parents Day
for the child in their first marriages
marriage they all come with their
spouses so the baby is called David the
mother is called Jinta the father is
called
Matthews Matthews Mar
Susan J marries
who so when David has a parents day in
school Jinta comes with the new husband
Matthews and
then David also comes with the new wife
called who
Susan and the child is so confused now
and Mommy will say this is your new
daddy daddy will say this is your new
what
Mommy and we will call each other baby
masam and baby daddies and it is gaining
acceptance very quickly today in society
have you noticed yes people can move
from one Affair to another give birth to
children and keep referring to 10 men as
they are baby daddies and is normal in
society today and we must be
sensitive to
you who has a child with a managed your
father we should be sensitive and we
should tell you the cross is there yes
the cross is there but you don't want
anyone to mention
it so we are redefining marriages we are
redefining today I can see a woman can
be 50 something and a man can be 30
something true or false
yeah and even the man did you know it is
the man that continues a
lineage a woman doesn't continue a
lineage a lineage is built by a what a
man
so now when you go and you're married to
a 53 year old woman who already
menopause why are you killing your
father's
lineage
why why are you killing your father's
lineage and you're comfortable and then
you'll hear them on Facebook and other
social media platforms they say if it
makes him happy that's okay that guy is
not happy they have happiness for
society but deep inside they're
broken and even some of us here are
being
kept by older
women
yeah
Ben mama
and she'll tell you if I find you
servicing another woman I will kill you
so you are very young boy hardly
23 there's a woman that has kept you in
some leafy sub you are servicing her
[Music]
so imagine you are
servicing no but for men it doesn't
matter men it doesn't matter they have a
saying in their world
men don't
care why a marriage is not working I'm
here to let us
[Music]
know and listen
keenly there is a marriage and family
blueprint
as given to us by the originator by the
Creator by the inventor of marriage
there is a blueprint for marriage and
family as given to us by the originator
himself but there is equally a
counterfeit blueprint as given to us by
the father of this world
Satan those are two blueprint
the question i' would like to ask you
are you conversant with these two
blueprints so that we don't sit here
arguing we could be arguing but all you
know is the blueprint from Saturn and so
we cannot agree because me what I know
is the blueprint from
God are you conversant with these two
blueprints not just marriage even
education we have blueprints for
Education we have two blueprints for
education there's classical education
which you and I have gone through a
blueprint of the devil and there is what
we call Christian education which is a
blueprint of God it was killed by the
church long time
ago and until we go back to that
original blueprint of Education we are
not raising any children for eternity we
are adding up to the ranks of the
devil until we go back to the original
blueprint of Education
and that is why you see this mess that
we have
today including Health there only two
blueprints we have a blueprint from God
which today the world would call
conventional medicine and we have a I
mean the world would call it
conventional medicine that is for the
world and for our blueprint you have
decided to label
it
alternative that is what you're calling
alternative Med it's alternative because
the other one any alternative let me
tell you the blueprints of God are super
Brands they cannot be
rivaled so today when you stand here and
start preaching about blueprints that
God gave us they will call you an
extremist they will call you a
conspiracy theorist
today you want to present the truth at
it is the church will throw you
out of course I know we have
extremists I know I'm
aware but if you come back with the
blueprints God gave us that the church
killed you will not preach on any pulpit
in this church
you will
not Ministry has gone beyond
pulpits and until we look for those
blueprints I'm not lying to you you will
keep calling us here to speak to you but
until you go back to the original
blueprints I'm not asking anyone to quit
their education don't get me wrong
I'm only saying we had our
Blueprints and until we get back there
we are lost
forever you can challenge
me and I'm not here to confuse
you I'm asking are you conversant with
the two blueprints of
marriage on which blueprint do you want
your marriage to operate on which one
much of what we have today many families
are operating on the blueprint of the
devil and that is why it's not
working so one of the reasons why
marriage is not working is because we
are operating on the devil's blueprint
of marriage it will never
work
never and like I'm saying chances are
our marriages are not working because we
have br broken the original blueprint as
given to us by God and we have adopted a
counterfeit blueprint given to us by the
devil we in an institution that we must
get a a situation that we must get out
of by all standards it's
pathetic when someone is asking how do
you come out of
I've seen a question like that um how to
deal with consequences of coming from a
broken relationship or a broken
family much of the bitterness people
would want
to
to looking for an English word it will
come you know someone is just so bit
about life but you don't understand why
is how they were raised they have come
from bitter
homes raised by a bitter
parent broken
homes they have seen it
all and some of you are seated
here beat about
life because of how you have been raised
it's not your problem is your Mother's
or
Father's there are people seated here
they are battling with the reality of
who is my father
they're almost
graduating it gives them pain in the
heart the last time they asked they were
told
what still looking for their
father they're trying to find identity
particularly for men women can get
married anywhere including China but for
men men want
see he came
back which are your roots and he had to
prove to the Americans that he also has
roots and had to find his home back
in you're battling with the fact that
your five siblings
your fathers are
[Music]
different and your mother doesn't want
to hear any question about
that broken
hores the last time you tried to connect
with your
father and people are beat
we're in a situation that we must get
out of but we must get out
right it's a terrible one but we must
get out
right this is not about us looking for
some quick fix symptomatic approach to
things no
that is why I have a problem when you
don't have a father and your mother
wants to introduce a father figure to do
what to do
what
Akuna you don't need interesting father
figures out here who have unable to
raise their own children now they are
your father
figure provided there's a man who wears
pants that is a father
figure just accept
you also are battling with the issue of
a father figure and then you come to
campus impregnant a
girl you continue with the same
cycle you yourself you're battling with
identity but you come to repeat the same
mistake your father
made then you run away I'm talking to a
young man
here whose pants are lose
if you ever impregnant a girl be man
enough to become a father at that age be
man what
enough and like I've always said if
you're not a man enough please don't
open the to if you cannot pay the bill
thirsty if it ever happens to you be a
man enough take
responsibility raise that child you will
struggle but you never know in the end
you will raise a beautiful family
because a child now has a father and has
what they call a never
abandon your child cannot go through
what you've also gone through it's
giving you pain and unnecessary
bitterness and then you also impregnant
a girl in campass and then you run
away the girl goes back home gives birth
comes back to campus with the same
child see all this my children all this
almost all I've raised them while I'm in
campus of course not your
age so I know what it means to be in
class and also have you have a child I
know natal is our first born then
there's a sevene gap before we had teach
when we realize we are getting late to
have children and I'd already quit other
professions to come back from Ministry
so when I'm coming back to do theology
we had a
Tish so has been born while I'm still
doing
theology so I've had two children while
I'm in campus doing two degrees ATO and
all of them first class owners so there
is no way you will tell me it's not
difficult yeah I've breastfeed tissue
and I'm doing greeker in the
[Music]
morning so it's not difficult for those
that have had children and still in
campass you can still manage a first
class H us with that child not at your
mother's here in
campas here in campus sorry you can
still manage there's an age 0 to
4 0 to 4 the education God gave us
starts from age zero 0 to four
the only thing a child needs is Mother's
love and care not grandmother's love not
Auntie's
love Mother's Love and what care zero to
what to four but do you notice how the
devil has corrupted us and has told us
we can give birth after 3 months we go
to work and we leave a child in the care
of a
stranger for the rest of their lives No
Love No care you live in the morning to
work come back late in the evening hold
your child 5 minutes they are asleep
leave early in the morning before you
see them and then we have raised
children that do not know what it means
to be loved and to be cared
for cuz they were never loved they were
never cared
for that's why it's so strange for us to
hug each other in the family very
strange very strange for you to hug your
father very strange for you to hug your
mother but the minute you learn in
campass from home
hey so easy so
easy so easy to hug someone in campus
than hug your siblings at where at why
because you never experienced it within
a home setup that is why when you ask me
is it wrong to stay in school for one
year it is not wrong because you have no
bond with those at home you don't have
it what you have with people at home are
Blood Ties but in campus you have life
ties with people in campus that's why
you you're comfortable being around
people you're with morning till evening
but at home the tie is not there it's
only
blood families have no time so stranger
there is no meaningful discussion we
have not bonded with our parents we've
not bonded with our siblings we've not
bonded with people at
home
yes and I'm saying let us not repeat the
same what m
let them enjoy your love and your
care it's called mother's love and
care anyone that tells you to separate
with your child within the those years
is killing the bond between you and your
child and that is where the devil messed
us up when he told us to leave our space
at home as women to go and work in the
office and today we cannot raise
godliness because the person in charge
of raising godliness is chasing what
money I've always said I have no trouble
with you going to school personally I've
G to school but if my education and
career comes first before my children
then it's all
wrong you will lose your children you
you see your parents have the money they
now have the money they have phds but
they cannot connect with you in fact
they are crying the parents that are
crying today
is and he's asking where did I go wrong
you were never there you are is chasing
a PhD to compete with the world now you
have the money when I ask you now bring
the money we Salvage your child it's not
possible that is why I say I was talking
about in the morning multiplication and
godliness under attack when we have to
leave our
space
flattered that there is a higher sphere
out there because we've acquired a paper
that cannot put food on the table
[Music]
he says
come keep that child bring her to
Compass with your head
high don't be ashamed of your mess on
it with pride
because you're in school to to make a
difference for any
soul that is badly in need of finding
rest like we are today
you must now halt for a
moment
stop I know you're headed somewhere but
now halt if you truly need rest for your
soul and take a deep
breath cuz it's not about the speed is
about the
direction it's never about the what the
speed you could be moving too fast but
in a wrong wrong
direction find the right direction
first before you can make any move
Jeremiah puts it nicely Jeremiah says
stand in the ways and see come to some
point there are many ways many
blueprints stand
see it says ask for the old
Parts yeah there is blueprint one
Blueprint 2 3 4 five all those are
always others will say the end justifies
the what is a
lie stand in all those ways say stand
there stand
halt we are now confused
see and says ask for the old Parts
because you don't even know which are
the old Parts ask for the old
blueprint where the good way is
and walk in it for you shall find rest
for your soul and I repeat until we go
back to the old
path that God gave us the old blueprint
we will never find rest for our soul
never never I know you'll ask me so many
questions I'll get you back to the old
blueprint have no interest in other
blueprints
but what did they say according to
Jeremiah we will not walk in
[Music]
it even after being told this is the way
they said we will not walk in it that is
the saddest
beat they
can't today many have asked for the old
Parts but are unwilling to walk in it
why because the old part
are
irrational they
insensible they're
impractical particularly for a
generation like yours that believes in
experiments laboratory experiments
you're so
hypothetical it must be tested to be
proven you think everything is science
you have carried the lab knowledge into
life I may not be wrong to
say there's a world of lawyers I don't
know why that world is difficult to keep
marriages I'm not am I the one who's
observing it
wrongly I'm not so sure whether I'm the
one who's observing that
it's a world of
lawyers marriage in that world is very
shaky have interacted with
some even when we've just gone to Java
to enjoy any slight discussion we bring
there's always a legal perspective to it
and this is only coffee why are you
bringing legal issues into
coffee so they're used to carrying the
corridors of Justice into the house and
when they meet they want to run marriage
like they're debating whether someone
killed or not they're
competing they have been taught how to
debate well so they carry the debate to
the
house the ways of the Lord are very
irrational very insensible in fact they
don't even make sense
impractical but that is where the good
way is
it is not enough to find and know the
truth it must be followed with prompt
and willing obedience else it can be a
snare instead of a blessing what's the
point of knowing the truth and you do
not live in obedience to it if you know
the truth and you don't live in
obedience to it it ceases to be a
blessing it becomes a snare
you must pledge to follow the light
wherever it may lead
you it may not make sense but just
follow because in matters of God
obedience precedes understanding in
matters of who God you obey first you
will understand after you have
obeyed in matters of
God though in many respects we have
swung into one early conformity in many
respects and step by step we have
advanced toward the
world but there is still hope praise the
Lord there is still what there is still
hope did you know we have even excelled
the world in doing their things HH we
have moved into the world until we have
excelled them we are worse than
them in fact they look at us and they
are shocked
fact
[Applause]
announcement happy Serv
not
burned from
speaking is bned from speaking
[Music]
pit it's very sad it's very
sad you don't want to be Associated you
don't happy
Sabbath praise the Lord
it doesn't need to get there it gets
there I said though in many respects we
have swung into worldly Conformity and
step by step we have advanced toward the
world I say there's still hope we need
not remain helpless and in uncertainty
no if we listen to God's voice and
follow his ways he will correct and
Enlighten us and bring us back to our
upright position of Distinction from the
world
we just need to listen to his voice he
will Enlighten us bring you
back to your position of Distinction
from the
world when you discern when you
understand the advantage of working upon
Christian principles and hide self in
Christ you will make much greater
progress are we together children of
God yes just understand two Christian
principle walk upon them hide yourself
in Christ you will stand
out so I'm just laying a foundation to
let you know we operate on different
different blueprints seek to find out
which is God's
blueprint that is on my work that is
your work seek it like you're seeking
actuo science seek the
truth you burn the midnight all for an
exam seek the
truth in the same
way so let me handle this presentation I
hope it takes care of many of your
questions I see these things they keep
adding
up what makes a good
husband what makes a good wife this is a
question that has made many draft a
checklist in a bid to search for a
perfect
M
Che must be tall
must be
tall he must be
handsome must be
dark must be
what must fear
God financially stable
everyone has their own checklist today
they even have must be a
Kiku or must be a
kissy you know must be a
Lu okay everyone has their own check
list I
know I
know no one person can have all the
things you're looking for that is a
reality if if you find a true Christian
chances are she's
[Music]
short if it is the degree you wanted
must be a degree older chances are she
knows nothing about domestic labor can't
cook can't clean can't wash
nothing chances
are I'm only saying you you can't have
it all together you
cannot but listen to me Genesis 2:18
allow me unpack it Genesis 2 Verse
18 Genesis 2:8 the word of the Lord
says it says and the Lord God said it is
not good that man should be what alone I
will make him a helper comparable to him
allow me unpack it very slowly one the
Lord says the Bible says it is not good
that man should be alone listen to me
carefully God created social
beings all of us are social
beings and the highest level of social
relation can only be achieved in
marriage and family the highest level of
social relation is only found in
marriage and
family this does not mean that
singlehood does not exist singlehood is
there and it is a gift singlehood is a
word but a very
rare rare gift
singlehood
exists as a gift but
very
prayer
so don't make yourself single when you
know you are
not you're burning with sexual arges
you're burning with
passion but you just want to
say single so how do you deal with your
sexuales
you get a
Samantha H how do you sleep with a
Samantha and then Samantha takes long to
respond
Samantha
yes I'm ready for
you yes
you can't say you're single and you have
vibrators sex toys you're struggling
with with masturbation you're struggling
with pornography and you still insist
that you are what singlehood is a gift
and so rare go ahead and
marry if you're burning with passion
look for a wife look for a man marry
don't lie to us here that you
single some people are single but living
married
life but they still say they're
single single
I'm pered and
Disturbed when everybody claims to be
single but living a married
life it disturbs
me there's a couple I was
counseling and the man just couldn't
believe that this girl is a
virgin the girl tells me Pastor he can't
believe believe it he
says is saying no one this guy doesn't
believe that virgin because himself is
not a
virgin virginity is not just about women
no so that men feel they can sleep
around only the woman needs to remain
chased no it's so easy to know a man
who's not a virgin so
easy yeah so easy you'll just know it on
your wedding night you will know
because a man who's not a virgin will
struggle to penetrate struggle
[Music]
struggle but if you want to know a
guru that's a guru
that's a
[Applause]
guru so this thing is not just for
women virgin still exist do they there
there are women that have kept
themselves and there are men that have
actually kept
themselves single
mother I'm not saying you don't marry
those women but I'm saying we have
people that have kept chest to De
they're still waiting for God's
time they're
there it is not good that man should be
alone speaks to to Adams
inadequacy and not evees in sufficiency
that's another topic we might handle
another day a man is not complete until
he has a Woman by his
side that one is a little bit heavy for
your
age a man is not
complete it speaks to the man's
inadequacy not the woman's insufficiency
when he met the
man all that the man needed when the
Lord says is not good for man to be
alone all that he needed to make him
complete he put it in the
woman so there is no way a man will
function without that which is in the
woman much needed for him to be
functional so when a woman leaves you as
a wife you go back to the stage or phase
of
inadequacy you just can't
function you can that's a heavy topic we
will handle it when you're ready for
marriage I'm talking to
Children it is God that determines both
the time for marriage and the person to
marry says it is not good that man
should be
alone it means he determines the
time I will make him a helper he
determines the
person not your mother not your father
not your
pastor it is God that determines when
you should get married and to who you
should get
married and
so I would say life is beautiful when
you align yourself in harmony with the
will of God it is important to know his
will and do it it is important to
consult with God before you make any
move whether major or in
significant find out what is God's
opinion about
this in his time he makes all things
beautiful let us stop leaving
presumptuous
lives the truth is if God does not begin
it he cannot defend it
and he has no business defending it the
problem with us today is we are
presumptuous with God maybe I'm using a
big term sin falls into three
categories when Christ was
tempted he was asked to turn stones into
what
bread we call it the sin of appetite
when he was
told to
climb that angels will take charge and
of course the devil was quoting
scripture in Psalms is it yes but he
didn't why because he was not going to
be presumptuous with
God being presumptuous means you
imagining that that is what God wants
when he has not expressly said
it some people have taken the experience
of OA to go ahead and marry
harot and say even HOSA married a what
hosa's
case was not presumptuous it is God that
say it I'm asking you when did you talk
to God and ask you to pick on a
h even when some people say you cannot
marry
interracially of course Ellen White does
not advise for us Maring
interracially like Caucasian and
black but I'm saying if God comes and
tells you pick a Japanese you will pick
as a matter of principle that it is God
that has done what has said but don't be
presumptuous with God imagine that that
is what he wants even when Peter wanted
to walk on water he didn't just walk he
was not going to be presumptuous with
God he said Lord if it is you ask me to
do what to
come many of us are imagining that this
is what God wants but if I ask you where
is the evidence you don't
have you
don't you just imagine provided him was
Min let me warn you something who said
nonbelievers are non
Adventists that's a tough question who
told you n believers do not be unequally
yoked with what who said
nonbelievers are non
Adventist who's
it did you know we have nonbelievers in
Adventist Church did you know that let
me give it to you very quick I know I'm
confusing you but you need to pull up
your
antai Christ gives a parable and says
someone went to sew and he sold good
seed is it and then an enemy came in the
night the same same Farm sold what sold
tears is it so there was wheat and there
was what do not be mistaken that there
is at any point wheat can be hair and
tear can be wheat no they're
distinct cuz wheat can never be wheat
tear remains tear and the disciple says
why can't we
appro and he says you cannot even when
the head because as they grow together
from the soil they look similar but when
their heads have sprouted you can tell
this is sweet this is tear and it is at
that point that the disciples are saying
let us go and remove the ones that are
tears because we can tell the difference
and Christ says no why because their
roots are already
intertwined if you pull the tear you
will pull out the what the wheat so
leave them until Harvest Time
we are God's
children in the world the church in the
world te are agencies of
evil they are right within the what the
chur so don't marry because of an
Adventist label because the tear also
has an Adventist what
label
H did you know we have wheat that is not
an Adventist out here my
sheep that is not of this
world yeah I'm not saying you go out and
I'm not saying you do PCM means
what preach convert
marry that is what I'm asking you to do
I'm only trying to say don't narrow your
mind to think nonbelievers are an
Adventist we have children of God out
here is only the truth they don't have
but once they get it they are better
Adventists than
you they just have the disadvantage of
the fact that they were raised Catholics
let me who asks to be born an Adventist
did you ask who asked to be born a
Catholic did you ask who asked to be
born a Muslim you just find yourself
you've been born a Muslim so you have no
reason to prejudice against anyone
because we don't ask where we are born
you're born an Indian and your religion
is
Hinduism what do you think that child
has to make a difference and that is all
they know and who told
you that they will not go to
heaven did you know that all these other
religions you will see and meet them in
heaven did you know
that for
it is not in my power to tell you who to
marry I am saying don't be presumptuous
with
God the Lord can send you straight to a
hot he has done it in the past he can
send you straight to a Catholic home he
has done it in the
past he can send you straight to a Hindu
or Islam home because he has a purpose
with you on that other
side I'm not giving you permission to
cross borders I am saying do not limit
the power of who of God and I'm saying
don't be presumptuous with him just do
what you're so sure it is God speaking
to me don't
imagine that is what I'm
saying that is what I'm
saying did you know it is our mothers
who came from K how many people come
from K here how many people come from K
just be proud of
K did you know it
is women that took adventism to the
other side of Nyan did you
know who took adventism
there women and when they got there they
just couldn't fit in those religions and
they started sabath school on their own
there's a particular Church they started
it's called a jigo who knows a jigo a
jigo has an interesting history a
history where until recently first
Elders were only women because it was a
church for women and children the
community refused and said they cannot
attend a woman's church but it was women
from Karo that brought
adventism into aigo today it stands as a
church
Adventist women who were married to
non-adventist but they took their faith
there largely this other part apart from
South adventism was transported by
women I'm making a
very you don't say moo said I'm saying
your husband might be out here and not
necessarily where in here might
be don't limit who God I'm only
emphasizing on the fact that don't be
presumptuous with God nonbelievers are
not defined by
denomination nonbelievers are defined by
the fact that they are not in
Conformity with the truth of God that is
an an
unbeliever even after you have given
them the truth they refuse to confirm
because they don't believe in that truth
do we have Adventists that have the
truth and that refuse to confirm yes
that's an
unbeliever children of God are out here
just because they were born Catholics
the day they interact with the truths
they don't even need anyone to convince
them they say I want to be baptized and
they're
Believers it's not about denomination no
Ellen White says the Church of
God is not a national
establishment the Church of God is not a
great or grand
Cathedral the Church of God she says is
not the various denominations he says is
where two or three are gathered and the
presence of God is right
there and you can bring your Bible I
bring mine and we open and we say this
is what the Lord is saying do we agree
to follow
yes see the little time of trouble is
coming where we will only have one
denomination ruling is it we will be
having Adventist Church there will be no
Adventist there will be no PC year there
will be there will just be one Church
operating in this world the Catholic
Church there will be no buying and
selling sa for those that have mark of
the beast you can take me
anywhere you will meet it even if you
take me to police you will meet
it it's coming the stage has been
set the church
[Music]
there will be they shall have all
collapsed including all the foral
structures of the church shall have all
collapsed we shall know a
Believer by the
truth not by our
denominations don't be I'm CH with
God and try to imagine this is what he's
saying when he's not saying and some of
us pray like
this yeah that's how some of us pray you
are not asking God to make a choice no
you are asking God to approve your
choice so you just like this one eye
open one eye closed at God I would like
to know if Mary is the
one God is insisting he not Mary he a
Tio but you insist it is
Mary because you want him to approve
your choice you're not praying to seek
his will you're praying for
God's approval of your choice
okay so it is important I say to consult
with God don't be presumptuous with him
if God does not begin I said he has no
business defending it he says I will
make him a helper comparable to him it
means a wife comes from who the
Lord the Bible says a good wife comes
from what the Lord not a good
woman listen again elsewhere it says
he that
findeth a wife not a woman wives are
made wives are
trained wives are
raised the problem we society today we
have raised intellectuals who are not
wife
material not a
woman and if you ever find a wife in the
essence of the word wife life you have
found a good
thing we have very few wives in the
world today very
few very
few you can talk to the
hand she's financially secure
so today we have men that have no
voice men
that have no
leadership there's always been a cry for
women to submit and I've always said we
don't submit to you because you're
male
no no you don't submit to a man because
he's
male we submit to you because the power
of of God rests in you as a man and it
will only rest in you as a man when you
fear the lord as a man that power is
what crushes us to
submission there's a leadership in place
but you see you're asking us to submit
into a place where there's no
leadership where is the leadership we
supposed to
submit I went to a school they are
electing student leaders is a mixed
school they have what we call
affirmative action for boys
hey do you know what affirmative action
is affirmative action we've always known
is for women where we
say that all seats have been taken by
men if we don't watch women will miss a
seat so we create certain seats
specifically for who for this school all
seats are taken by girls the school has
to create space specific seats for
boys affirmative action for
boys Society is done
dusted there is no Society without the
male
figure h i will repeat it there is no
Society without the man the day we bring
them to zero Society has
ceased and we must now raise our boys to
be
men
have
why a man can't talk today in the
house cuz a woman earns more than you
earn in fact you're
jobless two
months I look at you and I P you cuz
even even those job vacancies they're
not
there for the man it's not
there today is the women companies
employ more women than what than men
become it's not a joke it is
not an attempt to search for a wife is
an exercise in
futility you can't search for a wife
finite man cannot judge character you
and me if today we brought a woman here
and we now say judge her character will
you only God can judge our
character finite man can never judge
character as a matter of fact when we
are dating we all put our best feet
where forward
everyone of us wants to be good it's
until I
do that is when character now comes
out cuz it can no longer be
hidden finite man cannot judge character
that is why you cannot attempt to search
for a wife
you can't as a matter of fact a good
wife comes from the
Lord when the Lord says I will make him
a help meate comparable to him
comparable means
compatible one that suits you one that
matches you because only God can
identify this for
you the Lord knows you the Lord knows
the woman he is the only one that can
match make
you
can't all perfect gifts come from who
from the
Lord God's Perfection is not your
Perfection What God will turn for
perfect might not be what you think is
perfect but that is what is perfect for
you are we together
or the fact that someone knows who
God oh or the fact that someone is a
true
convert it is in this next institution
here
KU a man dated a
girl it was not of his tribe all the
years that were in campass he went to
introduce her at home parents refused
they said you can't marry a kiss they
Kal they said
where but they have they have been in a
relationship all throughout
campus so when the parents
refused this boy broke the relationship
got into another by the time I was
meeting this boy had five Affairs all
the five ladies have his children and
they don't know either
exists and he has sunk into drinking he
a mess was an elder of the church
[Applause]
[Music]
let's not be
stereotypical look for True converts
don't look for
tribes look for true
con you can never choose for yourself
a true convert must feel the need for
God to choose for him listen to this
quote from Mellen white Adventist home
43 paragraph 3 says marriage is
something that will influence and affect
your life both in this world and in the
world to come that is what marriage is a
sincere Christian will not Advance his
plans in this direction without the
knowledge that God approves his cuse
he will not want to choose for himself
but will feel that God must choose for
him I would not be understood to mean
that anyone is to marry one whom he does
not love no this would be seen But fancy
and emotional nature must not be allowed
to lead on to
ruin the Lord must choose for you don't
be driven by fancy and emotions
said this one is casket
ready cuz that is what attracts
you don't be driven by fancy and
emotions we are talking to the man cuz
it's a man that
chooses
don't I'm marrying what when my friends
see they will approve what are they
seeing what are they
[Music]
approving and then you confuse
artificial Beauty fori
I
it's the same yesterday it was in a
wedding I saw a
girl dress it was
fish but the butts were
huge she was very curvy too curvy for a
natural Cen and when she walks you can
see how the bladder is doing this n
fake you can
see you can just feel
see can notice this is fake
he
no one is asking you to marry a person
you don't love we are saying don't put
your emotions and fancy to the four
allow God to choose for
you water
cleans water washes but money cleans hey
in a glow
fory has cleaned her
up she can now eat good
food she can dress well
I'm about to finish Proverbs 18:22
says he that finds a wife finds a good
thing the word find in Hebrew is called
matter a transliteration of matter would
be m a t z a that's a transliteration
from the Greek
alphabet matter does not mean a
deliberate attempt to search
it means to bump
upon someone
accidentally did you hear what I said he
that finds a wife is not a deliberate
attempt to search but it means bumping
into someone
accidentally and that can only happen in
the providences of
God we call them Divine
Providence it is God that brings you
together under circumstances you least
expected you would be man and wife but
as you continue to relate in a honest
sincere friendship you realize that you
have an attraction for each
other you least expect there will be
your friends least expect
they would be your spouses because it is
God that has brought you
together fact even when you meet it's
never even in your mind you just like
them for
friendship and as the Friendship grows
you realize we can take it to the next
level but someone who just
says approach
grip
[Music]
this thing has nothing to do with grip
it has nothing to do with the size of
the
pennies nothing on men's side it has
nothing to do with the sign of size of
the Pennies on the woman side it has
nothing to do with grip it has
everything to do with how you play
around with that area as a man so if you
don't know how to play
around where is he
cm it has nothing to
do
nothing so let no one lie to you that if
you have a woman with big butts you are
okay we don't marry for sex no no no no
no no no no no
no we
don't those that are married will tell
you they are so tired sex is the last
thing in their mind so tired it only
sounds attractive when you're not
married the day you marry you think
you'll allow someone to to go three
rounds every night
you think you'll allow anyway you're so
tired so so
tired look at the things that drive
us you see a woman all you think is sex
[Applause]
you want to ask a
question let me just finish or you want
to give us your
experience I'm coming back to you don't
worry don't worry I'm coming back to you
don't worry don't worry don't wor don't
worry I'm just worried why you're
raising your hand at this
point there is nothing wrong in having a
checklist get me right nothing wrong in
having a what a checklist the truth is
it will not help you that is the reality
for every perfect gift of God there is a
perfect counterfeit from the devil and
so when the gift
comes you must now use the Divine
principles as revealed in God's word to
vet that
gift every perfect gift of God there's a
perfect counterfeit from the devil so
you cannot actually align yourself in
harmony with God's Will and the one that
will come could be actually a
counterfeit from where from the devil
don't be in a hurry now use the Divine
principles as revealed in God's word to
vet the gift that has
come this girl calls me and tells me
pastor
youth leader Le
so she's in an
affair with a young man who has a wife
and a
child and she feels deep inside this is
the man meant for
her I tell you the devil can bring you a
perfect
counterfeit now you need to gaug it
against the truth of the Lord as
revealed in his word and I told her
drop cuz this is someone's husband
[Music]
[Applause]
when it comes don't be in a hurry gug it
against the truth of God as revealed in
his word
the checklist is now the Bible as you
want to vet what has
come
okay make haste slowly is the advice
Ellen White gives us make haste what
slowly marriage in a majority of cases
is a most ging yoke there are thousands
that are made
but not
matched thousands meted but not
matched cuz they chose for themselves
take heed because what you think to be
pure gold can turn out to be Bas
metal while you may love do not love
blindly while you may do What Love do do
not love what
blind
don't
don't a young
girl they were not so sure if they could
be in a relationship with this man not
so
sure she's so bubbly but I love loved
her in a
bubbliness the
man proposed for an
affair but felt she was bubbly and
[Music]
then because she interpreted that as
he's not serious how did he go to que
this
que someone GED her what is g
G is
what what is
g someone did the
matchmaking and it is someone in
Authority someone you
trust a figure you look at and say this
one cannot mislead
me and because she didn't have a job she
just cleared from
campus this was the
this was the
bait the guy is
Rich she got
married they didn't last for one
year she
said which man is this you say he's
God-fearing but anytime we call for
Family Worship he doesn't want to hear
anything called prayer
doesn't this man now doesn't want her to
go to church an Adventist man and an
Adventist an Adventist man doesn't now
want the wife to go to J and he's saying
she's praying a lot she he does not want
her to pray like she's praying a lot
only to realize the guy is actually an
Illuminati guy
[Music]
but she's already
pregnant when they found out who this
guy
was the mother said I'm ready to take
care of my
grandchild send her back to school to do
her
Masters so don't marry because people
bear Adventist TXS it could be a tear in
the congregation
it could
be make Hast
slowly don't be too
fast I said while you may love Do Not
Laugh
blindly open your eyes
wide seek the face of the Lord
women have married and married
homosexuals I have several of those
questiones I'm sorting out someone walks
into your office and says he's Adventist
I didn't know until recently that he's
actually
having side relationships that are men
and when you now want to confront he
tells
you the question is tough when child of
God asks you should I quit this marriage
when they have just gone in they have
now three children four children is when
they're realizing that this man is
actually gay and they think they started
I said no he married you while he was
gay and he married for society because
there's pressure from society for a man
to marry and they will marry to cover
society's eyes but the reality is
they're
gay for children where do you want to go
while you may love do not love
blindly
don't women have been married into homes
they didn't know they were witchcraft
homes today they are battling in their
marriage only to realize they're being
asked and coed to accept the altar of
evil and if she doesn't accept they will
make sure you don't leave with their son
so you think you have trouble with your
husband but no it is trouble that is
Spirit induced so that you can be
discouraged and
leave because they want a girl who can
accept that Altar and continue with
it things you ought to have
known the Lord would have shown you but
you didn't want the Lord to choose for
you
because the guy is here he the treasurer
here the guy is the treasurer
here and we'll tell you my mother is the
first I'm repeating while you may love
do not love
blindly ask yourself will this Union
help me
heavenward will it increase my love for
God will it enlarge my sphere of
usefulness in this
life but many have acted as if the only
question for them to settle was whether
they loved each
other period Pastor I've gotten this
girl I love her she loves me we want to
word you ask her how old are you I am 30
how old is she
35 there's F
responsibility beyond the question of
Love marriage has more
to do with other things than just love
even those that divorce if you ask them
if they still love each other they do
but they have divorced it's not about
love as you may call it do you have the
knowledge do you have the understanding
do you have the
wisdom and where did you get your
knowledge from Hollywood
where did you get your
knowledge how do you understand
things how do you apply this
knowledge but if the only thing that
matters to you is I love him he loves
[Music]
me I hope I'll be able to question one
I'm done with
it trifling with people's
hearts never start a relationship that
you're not so sure God has
approved where does it begin you just
have to be a true convert to know that
God is speaking God speaks black and
white crystal clear if you can't hear
his voice the problem is not with him
the problem is with you
and it's so sad how I see young people
coming to me at the point of marriage is
when they look Godly cuz they want to
word all these other days they're not
interested in Godly Affairs they're not
they're
not they look so
Godly if you couldn't look for him
previously I tell you he will not speak
at the point of marriage he goes
quiet I'm repeating he speaks black and
what why crystal
clear and when he has spoken you have no
business wasting
time don't cour for too long 5 years
doing
what the longer you take you lower the
chances of ever getting married cuz
familiarity breeds
contempt and some of us will say we took
8 years because you were waiting for the
man to hit 27 cuz you're
26 the difference of one year and he has
to hit that
age for you for him to
marry to make for
long cuz he couldn't marry you when he's
24 and
23 after you have as
attained this is the wife or man God
wants me to have begin to coat You Begin
cting by asking her parents for her
hand you don't Begin cting by asking her
anyone that dates you not CAU your
daughter without your knowledge is a
thief
[Music]
Spirit of Prophecy says that never
attempt to cut anyone's daughter before
you ask for permission from her what is
my duty to know where my daughter is is
my duty to know who she is cting is my
duty to guide my
daughter but you can't just come from
campus pregnant and say this is the man
we want to get married and you you're
pregnant already people have married
cousins for confusing what they feel
between them to be loved when it's not
it's just an attraction that is actually
an attraction for a brother and
sister is a blood attraction but because
they have never met they feel that is an
attraction that can make them husband
and
wife my neighbor married a first
cousin while I was in
campass only for the mother to realize
this is her sister's daughter sister
you cannot cut my child without my
knowledge if you have prayed to the Lord
and the Lord has expressly told you it
is her tell her I want to meet your
parents she also doesn't even know what
you're going to do there what was meant
for
you because it is Lord directing it
to your
for is a sign of
respect I caught your
daughter that is why
begins and as you quot you're not cting
to know her there's nothing you know
about her or him you know each other in
marriage it is the Lord that has brought
you together he will fix the rest as you
grow in marriage just
quot because you know there are few
things you need to put in place so that
you can end up in marriage probably she
needs to know where you stay where your
home is she need he needs to introduce
you to their home
but 3 four
years I'm
one begin from there never caught
anyone's daughter without the knowledge
of her parents don't
don't how to deal with consequences of
coming from a broken relationship it is
the same thing I'm
saying we need to get back to the
instructions of God if all of us would
just wait for God to choose for us we
would been talking about broken relation
but because we are stiff NE people if
you're coming from a broken relationship
accept
why does it hurt those that have come to
me hurting I've always asked why are you
hurting the first thing they all say I
invested in that relationship and when I
ask what was the manner of investment
money
I invested finances did someone C you to
invest your
money you invested
willingly particularly this men that
would want to find an education of a
woman that is not your wife
don't find the education of a woman that
you know you have brought into your
house is your
wife don't try to F the education of a
girl
that is not your what your
wife I invested money why were you
investing
money when you're coming from a broken
relationship come to terms with reality
accept when you want to live in denial
it will bother you for a long time
you'll even kill people
just come to terms with the reality
[Music]
may rise up dust yourself move
forward accept you have been
left rise up dust yourself move
forward some
people
immediately what you know is that you're
acting as a
rebound she she's used to be in an
affair she can't function without an
affair
don't be
deceived when you come out of one
relationship sit relax take
time heal otherwise you will project
your bitterness to the other person you
are so bitter so you treat that other
person with bitterness because you're
coming from a bitter relationship sit
take a break heal be sober
[Music]
I'm emotionally
wrecked 21 years old
sit accept it happened
heal and then move forward but don't
jump into another relationship but as a
matter of fact I said there's no
relationship in
campass so if you're coming from a
broken relationship in campass that is
the end of the game finish
Compass don't get into another one
I think she has stood to let me know to
Tam Chaka
University Adam and Eve were the first
parents where did they Source The
Experience from and should we use our
own experience when parent what is
experience by the way when someone say
should we use our own experience which
own experience you've already parented
or what are you saying what are you
calling your own
experience let no one lie to you Adam
and Eve were beings that would be
visited by angels for instructions from
time to time they were not left alone in
the Garden of Eden they were instructed
from time to time by God himself and at
times By Angels even post Eden they
would still be instructed by
Angels okay
yeah but still my problem is
this you enter into marriage
green so
green back in the old days girls would
be taught how to become
wives and how to become
mothers they were
taught I don't know what happened
happened boys would be taught how to be
men and
husbands that generation
ended no one is talking about how to
become women I mean wives and mothers no
one no one so you guys have come to
University you have learned your
mathematics your statistics your
politics your what you know nothing
about how to become a wife how to
because even the person who's supposed
to teach you
was
empowered they went to Beijing today
they're in school they have no time to
meet
you educate
yourself educate your what don't go into
this thing
green the other day those who have
listened to me elsewhere we we have an
academy for marriage and family to train
you into this
institution just like you're training to
become a
pilot and a farm and
engineer no you agree with me none of
you can practice without the training is
it apart from this lawyer that practiced
law and has never been to any school of
no you need that training
so that you don't go there green so once
you go there you have a rough idea of
what to expect what you call experience
could be what you have learned from your
home which was not necessarily true you
were used to your father beating your
mother every
day and so for you to lift your hand and
beat your wife is not difficult because
it's normal women are
beaten that could be the only experience
you
have the only experience could be of an
irresponsible
father that is what you're bringing into
marriage your mother worked hard to be
where you are and so even as you get
into marriage you feel there's no reason
for a man to work hard or a mother
raised her so you expect your wife to
work hard like your mother worked hard
to raise
you the best experience is in the word
of God let no one lie to you that
there's is not training the word of God
has spoken about marriage and family
extensively Spirit of Prophecy has
spoken about marriage and family
extensively if you don't know is because
of ignorance and an abysmal willful
ignorance seek to know the
truth that we may raise a different
generation
student parent relationship again I say
there's nothing much I can do about it
seek to raise a better family than what
your father raised if you're not talking
with your father that is how they raised
you H there are homes where they were
raised when they see their father they
go running to meet
him some children take off his cup some
children carry his bag and they bring
Daddy to the house and they say Daddy
let's pray for you and some will take
off his shoes as we were raised my
father never took off his
shoes and we come and you take off his
shoes scrub his feet we didn't know he
was bonding with us my sister is here
will tell
you my father we scrubbed his feet and
when we finished he
said and massed his feet but there are
families where when the father comes
every everyone deser
yes tell me if you marry a man from this
home how will your marriage look like
it's a hard man
cold and then you say he doesn't show me
affection he was never shown affection
so he doesn't know how to hug he doesn't
know how to kiss the only thing he knows
is that is all he knows
then you're here discussing oh there
must be a foreplay to sex which one and
this guy saw his father and ran away
he's so cold about life because that is
the environment he was raised he doesn't
know how to touch he doesn't know how to
hug he doesn't know how to embrace he's
never experienced that thing he carries
it into marriage the reality is he loves
you but he doesn't know how to express
it so you'll only wait for the night
[Applause]
raise better children praise the Lord
praise the
Lord seek to raise better children a
friend of mine said he was distant with
his son who was in campass very distant
and he said one day
when he came home he just called him and
huged him it was strange to date their
clothes like this with his
father close like this he said the only
thing I didn't know that the only thing
my son needed was the Embrace of a even
men need to be embraced
even men need to be what embrace your
children let them grow in the warmth of
your Embrace are we together yeah let
them be close to you that is how they
will learn to express love but do you
know why our version of expressing love
is so materialistic is because we don't
know how to express love naturally so we
think there must be flowers is it yeah
we must be taken out those are very
materialistic ways of expressing love
love could only mean holding your other
person so
tight that is all they
need everyone wants to be
held could just been rubbing their hair
we rubbing there um just a touch here
for
women as we feel so good when we
touched yeah is better than a
flower Just a
Touch want to smile those that have been
[Music]
touched yeah and I know some of you are
seated here have never been
held not with parents not even with
friends on campus you have no experience
of a hug that is so sincere you don't
have it wish I could hug everybody
here you don't have that experience and
that is the experience you want to carry
into your marriage it will be so C so C
the question was is it right for
students to stay long without going home
even when there's no bond at home if
your parents never bonded with you seek
to bond with them are we getting it yeah
if your parents never bonded with you
chances are it's also because of the way
they were
raised seek to bond with
them seek to bond with them a young man
told me I have no bond with my parents I
have only two siblings we have no bond
whatsoever and just asked me can you be
my mother because we bonded so
well and I asked why would you want me
to be your mother and he said I just
want when you're praying for your
children and you're mentioning them by
name please mention mine as a
son today I told him you must go
home and I don't want to hear this
business you go home after 2 years or
one year I want you to go home quarterly
today he visits with his mother
quarterly seek to bond even when parents
failed to Bor just go
home the Lord will give you
wisdom on how to activate that Bond he
will so that you also don't raise your
children in a cold environment like you
were raised should we dewi Encompass no
how to know the relation ship is right
we have discussed you will need God to
discern spiritual
things if you have no God there's no
other way to discern spiritual things
are spiritually discern I'm not giving
you a shortcut there's no other way no
God you will know the other
pass and you will know his will as
Adventist should we celebrate
Valentine's
no cuz it's a pagan
Pagan it's p in
nature it's Span in
nature
Christmas Valentine's Good Friday Easter
Sunday they are all Pagan
festivities don't celebrate
them are we together don't do what
including New
Year the year never began in
January it was changed to January
so there are many things we celebrate
but they are pagan in
nature why do you need to show love only
on February
14th I need to be sh love every
day yeah
marry
me how will I propose to
her the guy says will you will you marry
me
[Applause]
sorry sorry sorry I want us to finish I
might not be able to answer all your
questions but I'm told there's a group
that wants to use this venue is it yeah
there's a group that wants to use this
venue so I would want us to to finish
this so that we can pray and go that
group give me one second just one second
so we are not celebrating Valentine's
what day we're
not we're not campus dating and is it
good to date a man 10 years older than a
lady again I say there's nothing like
campass
dating can you be married to a man 10
years older than you provided it's not a
generation
Gap generational Gap means 12 years and
above that is now a generational
Gap Spirit of Prophecy speaks about it
like
that
so that's a generational Gap and again
it shouldn't be so
little okay it shouldn't if you ask me
I've not read it anywhere but from EXP
experience 6 years plus you okay they
will say but mine mine is one and our
marriage is working I have no problem
I'm only saying as a matter of principle
Adam came first before who Eve so don't
marry a man younger than you otherwise
we will question which rib you came
from
[Music]
okay marry a man older than you
preferably I'm saying prefer those are
my thoughts you can even say
6 years
plus cuz women we think faster and it
will be so wrong for you to put every
agenda on the table and it is only the
idea of the woman that takes the
day women mature very what very fast
intellectually
you even as is Maring young wrong how
young is young what did you want to say
some people are 50 and they still think
they young and they're saying my time
will come you
old you B may mature both physically and
spiritually and emotionally as a matter
of fact age has nothing to do with
maturity you can be 50 and you an
idiot but again in terms of physical
maturity is also important cuz I don't
expect you're 19 18 16 and you want to
give birth our mothers did that but
today even your reproductive system is
not mature to to to give birth to a
child so like I said May 21 you're very
marriable 23 S 25
but for men 27 28 Kanda there's no
problem okay the best way to be in
courtship I've already explained that
but there's one thing you know you
people think courtship is about sleeping
kissing
he as I close this these questions I'll
go with them we will discuss with the me
when to come and answer them now that we
are under pressure to vate
I'm just answering that question
now concerning the things which I wrote
you wrote to me it is good for a man not
to touch a woman because is is King
James uses
euphemism hides what he's other versions
are so open is no good for a man to have
sex with a what a
woman nevertheless because of sexual
immorality Let each man have his own
wife and let each woman have her own
what husband because of sexual so I have
no problem I have no problem I have said
if you think you getting into sexual
immorality marry even at 10
years that is called exaggeration in
English I'm only
saying don't be 21 and still think
you're young but you are are so sexually
moral don't you are 2122 and you've
slept with everybody
marry but if you're not ready to take
care of bills I said close the water
Tob so the options
but don't get into
sexual
immorality that's the only thing I can
tell
you may the Lord bless us
may the Lord keep
us I pray you'll focus on what brought
you
here your
education and the fact that you gathered
as a group
of
Adventists that would want to build a
relationship with
God your
[Music]
the world know who you are before you
can get into any Affair some of us get
into an affair we don't even know
ourselves I cannot give you my daughter
when yourself you don't know where
you're headed where do you want to take
her
find out who you are interact with
people travel the
world then come back and say now I'm
ready for marriage
drop so have an experience of Life out
here how it feels like are you able to
manage can you raise a
family may the Lord bless us in Jesus
name Heavenly Father we glorify your
name we can't exhaust everything in one
day the Bible is a whole
Storehouse and that is why we are
admonished to seek your face through
your word daily every day we add one
truth to another every day there's
something to unlearn and many many more
to
learn there's nothing we have exhausted
here we seek that the holy spirit will
continue to instruct us even as he
brings to Clarity that which seems so
hazy your children are breaking from
this Hall of meeting
to engage in other things as they begin
this new week let it be packed with
energy let it be parked with
strength let it be parked with a
Vigor and a vibrancy that only Heavens
can supply May your children experience
a connection with you those that have
already lost hope in life and wouldn't
know what to do Lord I pray you meet
with them and once again breathe life
into their spiritual being and into
their physical beings may we stand out
distinct from the
world prepare us for your kingdom to
come because this is our prayer in Jesus
name am